https://adlerplanetarium.org/privacy-policy/

PURCHASE TICKETS
Your all-access pass to our universe!
Get Tickets
Page Select
Privacy Policy
Adler Planetarium Commitment to Privacy
Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we are making it available in the footer of every page of our website.
Information Collected
This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the Adler Planetarium website. It also applies to information collected or submitted on the Adler Planetarium’s WuFoo account. On some pages, you can order products, make requests, and register to receive materials, such as our electronic newsletter. The types of personal information collected at these pages can include:
Name
Address
Email Address
Phone Number
On some pages, you can submit information about other people. For example, if you order a gift online and want it sent directly to the recipient, you will need to submit the recipient’s address. In this circumstance, the types of personal information collected include:
Name
Address
Phone Number
Use of Information
We use the information you provide about yourself when placing an order or asking a question only to complete that order or answer that question. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order.
We use the information you provide about someone else when placing an order only to ship the product and to confirm delivery. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order.
We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties.
You can register with our website if you would like to receive our electronic newsletter. Information you submit on our website will not be used for this purpose unless you are asked as part of collecting your information.
We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and to share with partners. For example, we may tell an advertiser that X number of individuals visited a certain area on our website, but we would not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals.
Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.
Google AdWords Remarketing
This website uses the Google AdWords remarketing service to advertise on third party websites (including Google) to previous visitors to our site. It could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who haven’t completed a task on our site, for example using the contact form to make an inquiry. This could be in the form of an advertisement on the Google search results page, or a site in the Google Display Network. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Adler Planetarium’s website. Of course, any data collected will be used in accordance with the Adler Planetarium’s privacy policy and Google’s privacy policy. You may disable cookies using your browser settings.
Third-Party Sites
The Adler Planetarium has not reviewed all of the sites linked to its website and has no control over and is not responsible for the content or privacy policies of any off-site pages or other sites linked to the Adler Planetarium’s website. Any websites linked to or from the Adler Planetarium’s website are for your convenience only, and you access them at your own risk. Any information that you may provide to such third party sites is at your own risk.
Cookies
This website may use cookies. A cookie is a small data file that is saved on your computer to help store preferences and other information that’s used on webpages that you visit. The only personal information a cookie can contain is information that you supply yourself. A cookie is only a text file and cannot read data of your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Cookies can track user traffic patterns, recognize your computer’s browser when you return, and could provide personalized content without requiring sign-in.
This website uses the following cookies:
Google Analytics: This cookie allows us to see information on user website activities including, but not limited to page views, source and time spent on website. The information is depersonalized and is displayed as numbers, meaning it cannot be tracked back to individuals. This will help to protect your privacy. Using Google Analytics we can see what content is popular on our website, and strive to give you more of the things you enjoy reading and watching.
Google AdWords: Using Google AdWords code, we are able to see which pages helped lead to contact form submissions. This allows us to make better use of our paid search budget.
DoubleClick: We use remarketing codes to log when users view specific pages, allowing us to provide targeted advertising in the future.
Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. You have the ability to set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you a chance to decide whether or not to accept it.
While the Adler Planetarium may use cookies to track your visit to our website and our servers automatically log the IP address of your computer, this information does not identify you personally and you remain anonymous, even if you have previously submitted personal information to the Adler Planetarium through our website or otherwise.
Third parties whose websites are accessible through links on the Adler Planetarium’s website may also use their own cookies when you link to their site of service. The Adler Planetarium does not control these third parties’ use of cookies and cannot guarantee that the will uphold the same privacy standards as the Adler Planetarium.
The Adler Planetarium expressly disclaims any and all liability related to the collection, use or disclosure of information by third parties. You should review the privacy policies of any third party sites that you visit through a link from the Adler Planetarium’s website to understand how they use cookies and the information they collect through cookies.
You have the ability to opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.
Our Commitment to Data Security
To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.
Our Commitment to Children’s Privacy
Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain personally identifiable information on our website from those we actually know are under 13.
How to Contact Us
Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please send us an email at communications@adlerplanetarium.org. Postal mail may be sent to the Web and Social Media Manager, Adler Planetarium, 1300 South Lake Shore Drive, Chicago, IL 60605.
Further information and requests
In accordance with the European Union (EU)’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), the Data Controller is the Adler Planetarium. EU citizens can contact Adler’s Data Protection Officer (privacy@adlerplanetarium.org) with any questions or requests about your personal data.
Adler Policy Changes
Occasional changes may be made to this page as new services and content are added to our site or to reflect changes in the Adler Planetarium’s policies. Visitors to the Adler Planetarium’s website are encouraged to check this page periodically to stay informed of current Adler Planetarium privacy guidelines.
PURCHASE TICKETS
Your all-access pass to our universe!
Follow Us!
We all have the potential to discover something great. Help the Adler unlock the potential in every mind with a tax-deductible gift.
